vwdarkside.com 2013-05-13

# Privacy policy | Greenpeace UK

Greenpeace believes you have a fundamental right to privacy on the web, and we work to protect your security online as vigorously as possible. We have developed the following policy to help you understand how your personal information will be treated as you engage with us both on and off-line. Our policy reflects our duties under the [Data Protection Act](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) to use information fairly, keep it secure, make sure it is accurate, and keep it up to date.

This policy applies to all the pages hosted on this site. It does not apply to pages hosted by other Greenpeace sites around the world, or to other organisations to which we may link and whose privacy policies may differ.

Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated. It may change from time to time so please check back periodically.

This policy will let you know:

  1. What information do we collect?
  2. How your information is used?
  3. Does Greenpeace UK share my information?
  4. How secure is the information I give you?
  5. How can I access, correct or delete my data?
  6. How do I opt out of receiving messages from Greenpeace UK?
  7. How does Greenpeace UK protect children's privacy?  

  8. How can I find out more about my rights under the Data Protection Act? 

Our security measures and this policy are reviewed on a regular basis. If you have any questions relating to this policy, please address them to:

Chris Jackson   
Public & Supporter Information manager   
Greenpeace  
Canonbury Villas  
London  
N1 2PN

Tel: +44 20 7865 8183  
or [email us via the contact form](http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/forms/supporter).

If you are not satisfied with our response to your concern: you may wish to contact the [Information Commissioner's Office](http://www.ico.gov.uk/).

**1\. What information do we collect?**

We collect only information which you give to us via email, the various forms on the website, or information voluntarily given to us via telephone or postal mail. Some information is gathered when you join, make a donation, complete a cyber action or sign up to receive email updates. During these processes, the only information required is your name, address, phone, email (and payment method for joining or donating); although we may request other information such as your principal area(s) of interest in order to be able to provide you with a more personalised web service.

When you log-in to the Greenpeace UK site your login details may be stored on a 'cookie'. This is a tiny element of data that our site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive. Our web site uses cookies to customise certain options. This small amount of information does NOT contain any private information stored on your computer. For more information about cookies, please see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

_Anonymous access_

You can access our web site without disclosing your personal data but, if you set your web browser to disable cookies altogether, you will not be able to log-in and access the full functionality of the site. You need to be logged-in to make a donation, complete a cyber action, sign up to receive email updates, or leave a comment. When you leave a comment your user name will be displayed along side it.

**2\. How your information is used?**

Greenpeace UK only uses the information you give us to send you communications that may be of interest to you (either electronically or otherwise) if you have already opted-in to receive information from us.

If you have opted in to get email from us, you will receive regular updates every two to three weeks about our campaigns. If you have opted in to get involved in a local group, you will get communications from the local coordinator about events happening in your area. In some cases the communication is required by law, such as confirming a direct debit donation in writing. If you have made a donation, we will also send you information about our campaigns in the post.

We also use the information to help us understand more about how supporters use our site and make improvements.

**3\. Does Greenpeace UK share my information?**

When you are on our website and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Greenpeace UK alone unless stated otherwise. We will not share your information with third parties unless you specifically 'opt-in' and authorise us to do so. Greenpeace UK guarantees not to disclose any of your personally identifiable information unless we have your permission, or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**4\. How secure is the information I give you?**

Greenpeace UK uses industry standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers. We make every effort to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. In addition, we always use a secure connection when collecting personal financial information from you. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure.

Your Greenpeace UK member account is password-protected so that only you and those you designate can access it and view the member information relevant to your account. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. We also do everything in our power to protect your information off-line, and only authorised personell can view your data.

**5\. How can I access, correct or delete my data?**

At your request we will give you all details of personal information held by Greenpeace UK, once identity has been satisfied. Incorrect information will be deleted or amended promptly. We will give you confirmation of corrections and deletions.

We can only accept these requests if sent by email, fax or letter, after which we will take further steps to confirm identity before releasing data. We will respond to these requests within 20 working days, unless there are exceptional circumstances, and even then we will let you know what is happening with your request.

_Accessing and updating membership records online_

We are working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that Greenpeace maintains about you. We are developing mechanisms to give all our members access to their membership record online. In the meantime, you can amend your membership details by emailing our supporter administration team.

If you have any questions about the information we maintain about your supporter details please [contact us](http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/forms/supporter).

**6.How do I opt out of receiving messages from Greenpeace UK?**

We will only send you unsolicited emails if you have given us permission to contact you about other areas of Greenpeace's work. We do not send out random, untargeted emails (spam). If we send you unsolicited emails, the email will enable you to register an opt-out to receiving other emails from us. Any email that is sent to you, because we received your details from some one who recommended you to us, will clearly say this in the email.

If you do not wish to receive messages from us, please [contact us](http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/forms/supporter) asking that your contact information be eliminated from our databases.

NB By signing up as a cyberactivist or donor, you accept this privacy policy and authorize Greenpeace UK to collect, store and process your information in the ways mentioned above and for the purposes you submitted it.

**7\. How does Greenpeace UK protect children's privacy?**

The safety of children is very important to us. No information should be submitted to or posted at Greenpeace UK by children under the age of 13 without the prior parental consent. All applicable laws are followed with respect to data collection from children. No sharing of data collected from children with any third parties is permitted at any time under any circumstances.

NB Parents should be aware that owing to the nature of our investigations, images posted on the Greenpeace UK website may be considered unsuitable for children under the age of 13 (eg photographs of dead or dying animals).

**8\. How can I find out more about my rights under the Data Protection Act?  
**

The collection and use of personal information on this site is in accordance with the [Data Protection Act of 1998](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) ( UK) , and the guidelines of the [Direct Marketing Association](http://www.dma.org.uk/content/Pro-Code.asp) (UK). The DPA applies to all data held within the European Economic Area (EEA). We will only transfer data to an organisation outside this area if we have a contract with it which ensures that the standards set out in this policy are maintained.

Last updated: March 2007
